<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[aleksati.net / music tech and creative computing]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Part portfolio and part music technology blog. I write about audio programming, networked music, creative computing, software development, and more.]]></description>
        <link>http://localhost:3000</link>
        <image>
            <url>http://localhost:3000/img/me.jpg</url>
            <title>aleksati.net / music tech and creative computing</title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:23:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:3000/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 06:23:05 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Position Your Studio Monitors Better and More Accurately]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Improving the positioning of your studio monitors can significantly improve the sound quality of your studio. In this post, I share an easy and practical way to find optimal placements for your studio monitors with just some basic tools and a little know-how.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/posts/how-to-position-your-studio-monitors-better-and-more-accurately</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/posts/how-to-position-your-studio-monitors-better-and-more-accurately</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Measure Audio Latency in Networked Music Systems]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Measuring the audio latency of networked music systems is a complicated procedue where you have to navigate complex technical setups with many moving parts, usually on a tight schedule. In this post, I write about solid strategies and share good practical ways to measure audio latency in networked music contexts.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/posts/how-to-measure-audio-latency-in-networked-music-systems</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/posts/how-to-measure-audio-latency-in-networked-music-systems</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Audio Latency Examiner]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[A quick look into Audio Latency Examiner (ALEX); a software tool for batch collecting audio latency data from both musical software and hardware devices. The app is open-source and free to download, avaliable for both Windows and Mac.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/works/audio-latency-examiner</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/works/audio-latency-examiner</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dataset Generator for Musical Devices]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[the Dataset Generator for Musical Devices (DGMD) is a research project and software that can generate datasets from audio effects specifically for machine-learning tasks. This post takes a closer look at the DGMD software, including links to tutorials and download pages. Original post by Stefano Fasciani.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/works/dataset-generator-for-musical-devices</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/works/dataset-generator-for-musical-devices</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Software Poème Symphonique]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Modernist composer György Ligeti would have been 100 years in 2023. To celebrate, I recreated his famous 'Poème Symphonique for 100 metronomes' as audio software with a realtime ML-based sound engine. Read more about the process and see a full demo.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/works/software-poeme-symphonique</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/works/software-poeme-symphonique</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to use p5js and p5-sounds with Nextjs in 2024]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[I sometimes use the p5js libraries to make little audio-visual widgets and sonification examples in my posts. Recently, I decided to re-design and update my p5 and p5-sounds implementation to support newer versions of p5, React, Nextjs (v14.1), and TypeScript. Read more to learn how.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/posts/how-to-use-p5js-with-nextjs-in-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/posts/how-to-use-p5js-with-nextjs-in-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improve your Networked Audio Engineering Practice]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The success of a telematic event depends largly on the technician's familiarity with networked audio engineering, a field that is very different from usual concert tech. In this post, I share some steps and strategies that can help improve your networked audio engineering practice.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/posts/improve-your-networked-audio-engineering-practice</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/posts/improve-your-networked-audio-engineering-practice</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tools for Exploring Performance Patterns in Norwegian Folk Music]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[For my master thesis, I developed a series of interactive software tools to explore performance patterns in Hardanger Fiddle Music, in collaboration with the MIRAGE Research Project at UiO. Here is a quick look at the software and its main features.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/works/tools-for-exploring-performance-patterns-in-norwegian-folk-music</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/works/tools-for-exploring-performance-patterns-in-norwegian-folk-music</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[aleks.max - a Tiny MaxMSP Bundle]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[aleks.max is my small library of Max abstractions for audio, video and data processing. It's an on-going effort to publish some of my Max code that I believe can be useful to others.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/works/aleks-max</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/works/aleks-max</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring Dataset Sonification with Web Audio]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Thanks to modern browsers and open-source coding libraries, creating audio-visual art on the Web is easier than ever. In this post, I share some examples of how you can enrich your data visualizations with model-based sonification in a browser using the p5js library.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/posts/exploring-dataset-sonification-with-web-audio</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/posts/exploring-dataset-sonification-with-web-audio</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[0101101000 ... (hello world)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[A sound-sculpture made of burned drywall paper tape, methyl cellulose, aluminum flashing, bluetooth transducers, concrete and steel rods. The sculpture generates sound and vibrations based on the wifi traffic on-site. Made in collaboration with Henrik Nordahl.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/works/hello-world</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/works/hello-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Using Python to Control Ableton Live with MIDI]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[While designing a new liveset, I wrote some code to help me map and navigate Ableton Live more efficiently using very few MIDI controls. Here is what I did, and how.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/posts/using-python-to-control-ableton-live-with-midi</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/posts/using-python-to-control-ableton-live-with-midi</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5G Networked Music Performances - Will it Work?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[My collegue and I teamed up with Telenor Research to see if it's possible to play music together over next generation 5G networks. Here are the preliminary results from our first audio latency tests on private and commercial 5G networks.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/posts/fiveg-networked-music-performances</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/posts/fiveg-networked-music-performances</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karwowski, Kann & Tidemann + Nordahl]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[An improvisational audio-visual quartet that offers thought-provoking and immersive concert experiences, combining guitar, vocals, live electronics, and projected visual art.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/musics/karwowski-kann-tidemann</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/musics/karwowski-kann-tidemann</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AudioVideoAnalysis - Realtime Spectral Analysis of Audio and Video]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[A quick look into AudioVideoAnalysis (v2.0); a standalone software tool for real-time OpenGL rendering of video motiongrams and audio spectrograms, developed in collaboration with FourMS Lab at the RITMO research center, University of Oslo.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/works/audiovideoanalysis</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/works/audiovideoanalysis</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VideoAnalysis - Analyzing Music-related Body Motion]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[A quick look into VideoAnalysis (v2.1); a beginners tool for analyzing music-related body motion, developed in collaboration with FourMS Lab at the RITMO research centre, University of Oslo.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/works/videoanalysis</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/works/videoanalysis</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Radio 9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[A krautrock electronic pop trio from Oslo that takes you on a sonic journey from subtle electronic atmospheres to jarring post-punk whiteouts.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/musics/radio9</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/musics/radio9</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Holy Mountain]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The Holy Mountain is a dark synth-pop trio with accordion, vocals, synth and drums. Since 2015, the band has produced an impressive discography of critically acclaimed genre-defying music with a taste for the mysterious and transcendental.]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/musics/the-holy-mountain</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/musics/the-holy-mountain</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>